Email: rpanchivala60@gmail.com

Mobile No: 7021763810

#### **OBJECTIVE:**

To achieve high carrier growth through a continuous learning process and keep myself dynamic, visionary and competitive with the changing scenario of the world.

Ready to work with challenging assignment and responsibility.

To succeed in an environment of growth and excellence and earn a job which provides me job satisfaction and self development and help me achieve personal as well as organization goals.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

Six years of experience in developing web-based application using Liferay.

Profound knowledge of database abstraction layers, JSP and J2EE.

Hands on experience of frameworks like Spring 3.0, Hibernate 3.6, Struts.

Hands on experience of version control and build tools like Tortoise SVN, IBM Rational Jazz, GIT,

Apache Ant and Apache Maven

Experience with MySQL 5.7, MongoDB 3.4, MSSQL 2019 and Oracle 12c databases.

Has good knowledge in consuming Web Services like RESTful web services and WSDL-SOAP.

Hands on experience in implementing AJAX based solutions using jQuery.

Good Technical and interpersonal skills A good team Member and individual contributor Proactive, dedicated and enjoy learning new business requirements.

#### **EDUCATION:**

MCA (2014) from Gujarat Technical University with 6.9 CGPA BCA (2011) from HNGU with 72%

#### **CERTIFICATION:**

Liferay DXP 7.2 Back-End Developer

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

Application Server: Apache TomcatPortal Server: Liferay DXP/6.2/6.1Web Server: Apache Webserver

**Technologies**: Java/J2EE, Servlet/JSP Technologies, Liferay portal development DXP/6.1/6.2,

jQuery Object-Oriented Design, XML, HTML, JavaScript, AUI script, CSS, SQL

Web Services : RESTful Web Services (JAX-RS), SOAP based Web Services

Frameworks: Spring, Struts 2, Hibernate, Liferay 7.2/7.1/6.2/6.1

Build Tool : Apache Ant, Apache Maven, Gradle

**Version Control** : SVN, IBM Rational Jazz, Git **Development Tools** : Eclipse, Liferay Developer Studio

Libraries & Tools : jQuery, AJAX, Display Tag Library, Apache POI, Java Mail, Quartz

**Operating Systems**: Windows, Linux

Email: rpanchivala60@gmail.com

Mobile No: 7021763810

RDBMS : MYSQL 5.7, Oracle 12 c, MSSQL 2019

NoSQL Database : MongoDB

# **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

KNOWARTH Technologies 06<sup>th</sup> Jan 2015 – 20<sup>th</sup> April 2018 Designation: Associate Consultant

Reliance Jio Infocomm Ltd 23<sup>rd</sup> Apr 2018 – 11<sup>th</sup> March 2020 Designation: Software Developer

LTI – Larsen & Toubro Infotech 16<sup>th</sup> March 2020 – Present

**Designation: Specialist - Software Engineering** 

Project 1: RCRC (RDA)

# **Description:**

RCRC portal is to find comprehensive solutions to the traffic congestion problem in Riyadh city. Comprising a metro network and a parallel bus network, the public transport project in Riyadh city is being established according to the comprehensive plan for public transport developed by the RDA. This plan aims at providing all population groups with suitable public transport services, diversifying the transportation means in the city effectively and appropriately, in addition to keeping the use of private cars within the minimum limits. The project will be of great benefit to Riyadh traffic, economy, society, and environment. Moreover, it will provide the city with a giant public transport system to meet its existing and future needs.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Involved in Approach design and POCs for custom portlets and their capabilities Worked with DB schema design Manage REST Web-services response/request Liferay Plugins development (Custom portlets, Service builder) Built deployment, defect fixing, code integration and resolution Followed Agile software development process.

Environment: Liferay DXP 7.2 SP 1, MSSQL 5.7

Email: rpanchivala60@gmail.com

Mobile No: 7021763810

# Project 2: LCO Portal (DEN and Hathway)

# **Description:**

LCO portal is for managing cable networks and Wi-Fi networks of den and hatchway company. Portal manage users like primary, secondary and customers. Portal has some roles for activities, there are some integration with BRM (Business Revenue Management) portal that done through WSDN(SOAP) Services. There is a balance management activity is there which manages every user's runtime balance. There is a pack management activity is there where respective user can manage pack and subscribe for pack.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Involved in Approach design and POCs for custom portlets and their capabilities Worked with DB schema design Manage WSDL(SOAP) Web-services response/request Liferay Plugins development (Custom portlets, Service builder) Built deployment, defect fixing, code integration and resolution

**Environment:** Liferay CE 7.2 GA 1, MySQL 5.7

# Project 3: LMS (Learning Management System)

# **Description:**

LMS portal is for jio employees where employees can login and view announcements, can view their respective assigned courses, get information about new courses and popular courses respective to their fields, employees can post questions in message board, also get information about any topic in wiki, can view

blogs, also they can participate in any event or competitions, gamification is there so employees can earn points and get their rank and there are more activities to do for employees.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Involved in Approach design and POCs for Liferay OOTB as well as custom portlets and their capabilities Worked with DB schema design
Manage Restful Web-services response/request
Liferay Plugins development (Custom portlets, Service builder)
Client-side rich UI development using jQuery, bootstrap, and Ajax
End to end server's setup
Built deployment, defect fixing and resolution

Environment: Liferay CE 7.1 GA 2, MySQL 5.7

Email: rpanchivala60@gmail.com

Mobile No: 7021763810

### **Project 4: RMC (Reliance Media Center)**

# **Description:**

RMC portal is for handling media news for reliance and its subsidiary companies where media person

can login and feed the news about reliance and there were bulk news uploading functionality is there so

media person can upload media news as well as TV news, user can upload magazine news with photos, in some cases there is a media house API integration is there for auto upload the news at certain times of day.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Involved in Approach design and POCs for Liferay OOTB as well as custom portlets and their capabilities

Worked with DB schema design Liferay multiple node cluster setup

Manage Restful Web-services response/request

Liferay Plugins development (Custom portlet, Service builder)

Client-side rich UI development using jQuery and Ajax

Built deployment, defect fixing and resolution

**Environment:** Liferay CE 6.2, MySQL 5.7

# Project 5: Jio GST Description:

Jio GST portal is completely CMS portal where user can get information about GST. Portal provides information about what are the eligible criteria of GST, to whom GST will applied and many more content and documents are given in portal. There are two types of user registration is there taxpayer and tax consultant for GST registration. Taxpayer can apply for self-tax registration and tax consultant can apply for a group of users for tax registration.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Direct client Interaction for Sprint requirement analysis

Involved in Approach design and POCs for Liferay OOTB as well as custom portlets and their capabilities

Worked with DB schema design

Liferay multiple node cluster setup

Manage Restful Web-services response/request

Liferay Plugins development (Custom portlet, Service builder)

Client-side rich UI development using jQuery and Ajax

Built deployment, defect fixing and resolution

**Environment:** Liferay 6.2 CE, MySQL 5.7

Email: rpanchivala60@gmail.com

Mobile No: 7021763810

#### **Project 6: Jio Partner Central**

# **Description:**

Jio partner central is complete partner's communication portal where there is a partners and employees user hierarchy maintained. Authorized Employees can send communication to their respective partners regarding new schemes and offers of jio products and there is a hierarchy where low level partner can send their queries to high level authorities. Schedulers are maintained to send schema notification to employees and for send communication to partners.

# Responsibilities:

Direct client Interaction for Sprint requirement analysis

Liferay plug-ins development experience including custom portlets, hooks etc.

Administration activities for Liferay portal

Liferay multiple node cluster setup

Manage Restful and SOAP based Web-services response/request

Good hands on experience for Liferay permission system, Organization, communities, user, user-groups and Roles related activities

Co-ordination with team member for Liferay Issues

**Environment:** Liferay EE 6.2 GA6, Oracle 12c

## **Project 7: Jio Community**

#### **Description:**

Jio community is all about community forum portal, where user can post their questions or queries and also there is a functionality where user can also reply the answer of questions which is posted by other users, gamification is also additional feature for user interest. Added workflow for forum posts where only approved posts are display.

#### Responsibilities:

Direct client Interaction for Sprint requirement analysis

Involved in Approach design and POCs for Liferay OOTB as well as custom portlets and their capabilities

Liferay plug-ins development experience including custom portlets, Hooks, Theme, Ext, service-builders etc.

Administration activities for Liferay portal

Good hands on experience for Liferay permission system, Organization, communities, user, usergroups and Roles related activities

Co-ordination with team member for Liferay Issues

Liferay Web content and associated kaleo workflow with it

Environment: Liferay 6.2 EE GA6, Oracle 12c

Email: rpanchivala60@gmail.com

Mobile No: 7021763810

Project 8: IpageMD

**Description:** 

IpageMD is complete hospital management solution web portal, where patients histories and schedules are maintained, like what type of daises patient have, which doctor is attending which patient as well as what is the patient's daises test results, likewise doctors history and schedules also maintained through the portal.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Understanding the entire business requirement and implementing in Liferay portal Involved in Approach design and POCs for Liferay OOTB as well as custom portlets and their capabilities development

**Environment:** Liferay 6.2 CE GA2, MySQL 5.5, Spring facade (Produce Web Service)

# **Project 9: HBE- Heartbeat Experts**

#### **Description:**

HBE is complete hospital solution where multiple hospitals can be handled from central HBE portal, portal enables user to Create dynamic theme of multiple portal instance under HBE portal as per template selected by hospital instance site owner, user can modify own site layout and also can change color schema of site.

# Responsibilities:

Understanding the entire business requirement and defining UI mock-ups and implementing in Liferay portal

Involved in Approach design and POCs for Liferay OOTB as well as custom portlets and their capabilities

Extensive use of Liferay database shard

Environment: Liferay 6.2 CE GA2, MySQL 5.5

# Project 10: Trinet

#### **Description:**

Trinet is intranet portal for handling company activities like HR, BD, Finance and Marketing. Portal shows what activities were done and list of task or events in queue for execution.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Implement POCs
Provide technical solutions
Discuss and resolve Impediments
Deliver stories on time

**Environment:** Liferay 6.2 CE GA2, MySQL 5.5

Email: rpanchivala60@gmail.com

Mobile No: 7021763810

# Project 11: RMS - Resource Management System

# **Description:**

Resource management system is complete solution of managing resources of organization, system enables user to add resources and view current tasks of resources. System shows dashboard that helps to find resources statistics and shows future tasks. System enables functionality to assign resource to any task or we can say that resource tasks can be scheduled. RMS enables organization to schedule the task of resources very efficiently.

#### **Responsibilities:**

Implement Business, Service and DB layers. Provide technical solutions Interaction Defect Fix

Environment: Liferay 6.1 CE GA2, MySQL 5.5

# **PERSONAL PROFILE:**

Date of Birth: 15<sup>th</sup> Jan 1991

**Gender:** Male

Marital Status: Single

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Gujarati

**Nationality:** Indian

Declaration: I state that the above facts are true, correct, and complete to the best of my knowledge

and belief.

Place: Ahmedabad Rahul A. Panchivala